Guide to the Nicole Baran Papers SC1269
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
- Papers, Accession ARCH-2015-156
  - Center Handouts, Series 9
    - Handouts
      - Alcohol and Sexual Assault: The Connection (Box 21)
      - Backlash Handouts (Box 21)
      - Barriers to Leaving (Box 21)
      - Brainstorm Tactics (Box 21)
      - Batterers (Box 21)
      - BIP Handouts (Box 21)
      - CA Handouts (Box 21)
      - Case Scenarios: RDs (Box 21)
      - Case Scenarios (1-3 Dyad and A-D Guide) (Box 21)
      - Case Scenarios and Instructions for Actors (Box 21)
      - Case Scenarios: Judicial Affairs (Box 21)
      - Case Scenarios: Natali/Dyad Activity/B C (Box 21)
      - Children (Box 21)
      - Legal Bias Against Rape Victims (Box 21)
      - Mandatory Reporting and DV (Box 21)
      - Lyrics – "Love the Way You Lie" (Box 21)
      - MAAN Member Packet (Box 21)
      - Men Handouts (Box 21)
      - Model Workplace Policy (Box 21)
      - The Rules/Paperfold (Box 21)
      - Oh the Places Scripts (Box 21)
      - PHE Handouts (Box 21)
      - Possible Responses (Box 21)
      - Power and Control Wheels (Box 21)
      - Protocols (Box 21)
      - Rape Myth Statements (Box 21)
      - Red Flags/Brainstorm (Box 21)
      - Resources for Health Care Providers (Box 21)
      - Responding to Relationship Abuse: Who to Call (Box 21)
      - Student Quotes (Box 21)
      - Safety Planning (Box 21)
      - Safety Planning Form (Box 21)
      - Paper Fold Template (Box 21)
      - RA Handouts (Box 21)
      - Sign-Up Sheets (Box 21)
      - Safety Planning for Adult Survivors (Box 21)
      - Safety Planning with Children (Box 21)
      - Same-Sex Handouts (Box 21)
      - Supportive Interventions (Box 21)
      - "Untold Stories of Sexual Assault at Duke" (Box 21)
      - Saturday Night: Untold Stories (Box 21)
      - Resource Checklist (Box 21)
      - Tech Safety (Box 21)
      - Teen Domestic Violence Poems (Box 21)
      - The Rules/Good Wife's Guide (Box 21)
      - The Rules/Red Flags (Box 21)
      - Types of Abuse (Box 21)
      - VAW Fact Sheet (Box 21)
      - Victim Blaming (Box 21)
      - Victim Blaming (Box 21)
      - Warning Signs/Red Flags (Box 21)
      - What Is Wrong with Mutual Orders… (Box 21)
      - What Men Can Do to Stop Relationship Abuse (Box 21)
      - Judicial (Box 21)
      - A - Medical Packet 1 (Box 21)
      - A - Medical Packet 2 (Box 21)
      - A - Medical Packet 3 (Box 21)
      - B - Medical Packet 1 (Box 21)
      - B - Medical Packet 2 (Box 21)
      - B - Medical Packet 3 (Box 21)
      - Dating Violence Post Test (Box 21)
      - Healthy Relationships (Box 21)
      - Teen Resources (Box 21)
      - How to Help (Box 21)
      - David/Maria (Box 21)
      - Judicial Affairs (Box 21)
      - MSW 2006 (Box 21)
      - MSW 2007 (Box 21)
      - RA Packets 2008 (Box 21)
      - Center Handout Binder (Box 21)
        - Warning Signs/Types (Box 21)
        - Power and Control Wheels (Box 21)
        - How to Help and Safety Planning (Box 21)
        - Perpetrators/Accountability (Box 21)
        - Men (Box 21)
        - Sexual Assault (Box 21)
        - Legal (Box 21)
        - Children (Box 21)
        - Activism (Box 21)
        - Gender/Backlash (Box 21)
        - LGBTQ (Box 21)
        - Case Scenarios (Box 21)
        - Activities (Box 21)
        - Eval/Quiz (Box 21)
        - Center Docs (Box 21)
  - Domestic Violence Research Articles, Series 10
    - Domestic Violence Research Articles
      See Box 26 for research articles on dating violence, mandatory arrest and couples counseling; see Box 24 for research articles on Economic Self-Sufficiency for Battered Women.
      - Article Search (Box 2)
      - Article Briefs (Box 2)
      - Therapy/Psych Articles (Box 2)
      - Rethinking Domestic Violence Research (Box 2)
      - Database – New Articles (Box 2)
      - Batterers (Box 2)
      - College (Box 2)
      - Stalking (Box 2)
      - Sexual Assault (Box 2)
      - Rape – Possibilities for Change (Box 2)
      - Rape and Law (Box 2)
      - Sex and Alcohol (Box 2)
      - Domestic Violence and Parenting (Box 2)
      - Children (Box 2)
      - CPS Guidelines (Box 2)
      - Data Collection Methods (Box 2)
      - Statistics (Box 2)
      - Backlash: Gender Neutrality (Box 2)
      - Domestic Violence and Economic Empowerment (Box 2)
      - EMDR (Box 2)
      - Trauma (Box 2)
      - Cognitive Behavioral Therapy (Box 2)
      - Restorative Justice (Box 2)
      - Feminist Therapy (Box 2)
      - Feminism (Box 2)
      - Same-Sex DV (Box 2)
      - Socioeconomic (Box 2)
      - Rape Reporting (Box 2)
      - Religion (Box 2)
      - Race/Ethnicity (Box 2)
      - Disabilities (Box 2)
      - Mental Health (Box 2)
      - Domestic Violence and Social Work/Counseling (Box 2)
      - Domestic Violence and Law (Box 2)
      - Domestic Violence and Health Profession (Box 2)
    - Amnesty International
      - Juarez/Chihuahua (Box 2)
      - Juarez Spanish - Talking Points (Box 2)
      - Fact Sheet Juarez/Letters (Box 2)
      - Fact Sheet on Sexual Violence (Box 2)
      - General Fact Sheet (Box 2)
  - Curriculum/Training Materials/Resources by Topic (External Information), Series 11
    - Curriculum/Training Materials/Resources by Topic (External Information) (Box 6)
    - MCADV: Nature Dynamics Manual (Box 6)
    - The Rules (Box 6)
    - Greenbook Guidelines (Box 6)
    - Sample Presentations (Box 6)
    - Sexual Assault (Box 6)
    - Speeches (Box 6)
    - Social Work Domestic Violence Manual – Online Course (Box 6)
    - Workplace (Box 6)
    - Working with Batterers (Box 6)
    - Fraternities (Box 6)
    - Men's Curriculum (Box 6)
    - Mandatory Arrest (Box 6)
    - Sexual Harassment (Box 6)
    - Health Surveys (Box 6)
    - Literature Examples (Box 6)
    - Myths and Realities (Box 6)
    - Military and Violence (Box 6)
    - News Articles (Box 6)
    - Organizing College Campuses (Box 6)
    - Role Plays (Box 6)
    - Crisis Intervention/Hotline (Box 6)
    - La Casa Handouts (Box 6)
    - La Casa Presentation (Box 6)
    - Confidentiality and Info Sharing (Box 6)
    - COPS – College Rape (Box 6)
    - Mentors in Violence Prevention/JK (Box 6)
    - Culture – Health (Box 6)
    - Starting a Nonprofit Info (Box 6)
    - Mental Health (Box 6)
    - Culture (Box 6)
    - Dating Violence/Teens (Box 6)
    - Teen Dating Violence (Box 6)
    - Energizers (Box 6)
    - Expert Witness (Box 6)
    - Family Law and Domestic Violence (Ken Theisen) (Box 6)
    - Housing (Box 6)
    - Immigrant (Box 6)
    - Legal (Box 6)
    - Legal Overview (Box 6)
    - LGBT (Box 6)
    - Legal Bias – Dialogue (Box 6)
    - Legal Handouts (Box 6)
    - Workplace Handouts (Box 6)
    - Action Tips (Box 6)
    - Dating Intervention: Baran Articles (Box 6)
    - Staff Articles (Box 6)
    - Lethality Assessment (Box 6)
    - Causes and Theory of DV (Box 6)
    - VAW Education Project 2004 (Box 6)
    - Policy Advocacy (Box 6)
    - Law Enforcement (Box 6)
    - Law Enforcement Info (Box 6)
    - Bancroft Work (Box 6)
    - CALCASA – Law Enforcement Training (Box 6)
    - SCC Law Enforcement Domestic Violence Protocol (Box 6)
    - Domestic Violence Protocol 2009 (Box 6)
    - BIP Standards (Box 6)
    - Magazine Article Originals (Box 6)
    - Powerline Activity (Box 6)
    - Children and DV (Box 6)
    - CRISIS Hotline Procedures (Box 6)
    - College Exercises (Box 6)
    - Coding and Documentation of Domestic Violence (Box 6)
    - National Health Resource Center on Domestic Violence: (Box 6)
    - Improving Health Care Response to Domestic Violence (Box 6)
    - A Domestic Violence Campus Organizing Guide for Health Professional Students and Faculty (Box 6)
    - A Call to Action: The Nursing Role in Routine Assessment for Intimate Partner Violence (Box 6)
    - Advocacy Matters: Helping Mothers and their children (Box 6)
    - Family Team Conferences in Domestic Violence Cases (Box 6)
    - Creating a Domestic Violence Court (Box 6)
  - External Resources and Brochures, Series 12
    - Local Resources/Brochures (Box 10)
    - Stanford Resources - Brochures (Box 10)
    - Student/Campus Publication (Box 10)
    - 3rd Party Resources (Box 10)
    - Resources (Box 10)
    - Resources (Box 10)
  - Training and Curriculum Development, Series 13
    - Health Care Presentation (Box 10)
    - FVPF Work to End Domestic Violence Organizers Kit (Box 10)
    - Enhancing Dental Professionals' Response to Domestic Violence (Box 10)
    - A Domestic Violence Campus Organizing Guide for Health Professional Students and Faculty (Box 10)
    - Resources (Box 10)
    - Program Ideas (Box 10)
  - Curriculum Building by Topic, Series 14
    - Judicial Institute (Box 10)
    - Family Law and Domestic Violence (Box 10)
    - Domestic Violence Response Cross-Training (Box 10)
    - Break the Cycle Curriculum (Box 10)
    - 40-hour Core Curriculum (Box 10)
    - Bystander (Box 10)
    - The Campus Advocate: Vol. 1: Bystander (Box 10)
    - Stanford Greek RAP 1994 (Box 10)
    - Training Manuals Table of Contents (Box 10)
      Includes 19 different training manuals' table of contents.
    - External Guidelines Table of Contents (Box 10)
    - VAWNet Training/Curriculum Resources (Box 10)
    - Batterer Accountability and Children Initiative (Box 10)
    - BIP Curriculum (Box 10)
    - BIP Info (Box 10)
    - Sexual Assault Journal (Duke) (Box 10)
  - Family Violence Prevention Fund Training Manuals, Series 15
    - Family Violence Prevention Fund: Screen to End Abuse (CD) (Box 5)
    - Family Violence Prevention Fund: Media/Camera Ready Art (CD) (Box 5)
    - Improving the Health Care Response to Domestic Violence (Box 5)
    - Domestic Violence: A National Curriculum for Family Preservation Practitioners (Box 5)
    - Improving the Health Care Response to Domestic Violence (Box 5)
    - Rompiendo el Silencio (Box 5)
    - Enhancing Judicial Skills in Domestic Violence Cases (Box 5)
    - Improving Your Community Clinics Response to Domestic Violence (Box 5)
    - Cultural Considerations in Domestic Violence Cases (Box 5)
    - Family Violence Prevention Fund: Working with Battered Immigrant Women (Box 5)
    - Workplace (Box 5)
    - Identifying and Responding to Domestic Violence (Box 5)
    - National Consensus Guidelines on Identifying and Responding to Domestic Violence Victimization in Health Care Settings (Box 5)
    - Hanging Out or Hooking Up (Box 5)
    - National Health Care Standards Campaign on Family Violence: Model Practices from 15 States (Box 5)
    - Accountability and Connection with Abusive Men (Box 5)
    - Creating a Domestic Violence Court (Box 5)
    - Promoting Prevention, Targeting Teens (Box 5)
    - Family Teen Conferences in Domestic Violence Cases (Box 5)
    - Advocacy Matters: Helping Mothers and Their Children (Box 5)
    - Making the Connection: Domestic Violence and Public Health (Box 5)
    - The Business Case for Domestic Violence Programs in Health Care Settings (Box 5)
  - External Training Manuals, Series 16
    See Box 3 for Freedom From Violence: Preventing Violence against Women with Disabilities guides; see box 28 for MVP (Mentors in Violence Prevention) Trainer's Manual; see Box 26 for And Justice for All: Court Advocacy with Victims of Domestic Violence Training Manual.
    - External Training Manuals (Box 4)
    - Campus Program Training Technical Assistance Institute for Campus Disciplinary Judicial Boards, 2011 Summer (Box 4)
      Amy Pohl, Center Program Director, attended
    - LGBT Manual (Box 4)
    - T.O.P Teen Dating Violence (Box 4)
    - POST Advanced Training Committee (Box 4)
    - Organizing College Campuses (Box 4)
    - CPS (Box 4)
    - NCHERM Sexual Misconduct JA Training (Box 4)
    - Barbara J. Hart's Collected Writings (Box 4)
    - Somewhere to Turn: Making Domestic Violence Services Accessible to Battered Immigrant Women: A "How To" Manual for Advocates (Box 4)
    - Domestic Violence Response Cross-Training Institute: Trainer's Manual, Spring 2008 (Box 4)
      Baran's father was a trainer on this; he joined the Domestic Violence field as an attorney in 2005. He received some of his training from Baran.
  - External Training Manuals/Pamphlets/Guidelines, Series 17
    - Family Violence Prevention Fund Pamphlets and Action Kits
      - Coaching Boys into Men: Playbook (Box 8)
      - Health Cares About Domestic Violence Day: Organizing Packet (Box 8)
      - Connect: Helping Parents Talk to Kids about Violence Against Women (Box 8)
      - Connect: Helping Parents Talk to Kids about Violence Against Women (Issue 2) (Box 8)
      - Coding and Documentation of Domestic Violence (Box 8)
      - Summary of New Federal Medical Privacy Protections for Victims of Domestic Violence (Box 8)
      - National Health Resource Center on Domestic Violence: Responding to Diversity (Box 8)
      - National Health Resource Center on Domestic Violence: Workplace Response to Domestic Violence (Box 8)
      - National Health Resource Center on Domestic Violence: The Primary Care Response to Domestic Violence (Box 8)
      - National Health Resource Center on Domestic Violence: Teen Dating Violence (Box 8)
      - National Health Resource Center on Domestic Violence: Responding to Domestic Violence in Lesbian, Gay, Transgender and Bisexual (LGTB) Communities (Box 8)
      - National Health Resource Center on Domestic Violence: Responding to Violence against People with Disabilities (Box 8)
      - Health Resource Center on Domestic Violence (Box 8)
      - Improving the Healthcare Response to DV (Box 8)
      - A Domestic Violence Campus Organizing Guide for Health Profession Students and Faculty (Box 8)
      - A Call to Action: The Nursing Role in Routine Assessment for Intimate Partner Violence (Box 8)
    - Training Curriculum, Pamphlets and Resource Guides
      - Student Government Representations (Box 8)
      - Campus and Local Law Enforcement/Security Officers (Box 8)
      - Deans and Administrators (Box 8)
      - Faculty and Teaching Assistants (Box 8)
      - Health Center Staff (Box 8)
      - Judicial Affairs Representatives (Box 8)
      - Peer Educators (Box 8)
      - Presidents, Chancellors and Provosts (Box 8)
      - Resident Assistants/Resident Advisors (Box 8)
      - Greeks and Athletes (Box 8)
      - Ms. Foundation for Women: Safety Program (Box 8)
      - Social Work (53.4 p289-384), 2008 Oct (Box 8)
      - Resource Center on Domestic Violence: Child Protection and Custody (Box 8)
      - Sexual Violence in Disasters (Box 8)
      - It's In Our Hands: Stop Violence against Women (Amnesty International) (Box 8)
      - Lives Blown Apart: Crimes against Women in Times of Conflict (Amnesty International) (Box 8)
      - CEDAW: The Treaty for the Rights of Women (Box 8)
      - The Green Book: Effective Intervention in Domestic Violence and Child Maltreatment Cases: Guidelines for Policy and Practice (Box 8)
      - Domestic Violence: The Law Enforcement Guide: Student Guide (Box 8)
      - Domestic Violence: The Law Enforcement Guide: Instructor Manual (Box 8)
      - Building Academic Capacity and Expertise in the Health Effects of Violence and Abuse (Box 8)
      - Working with Battered Women in Jail (Box 8)
      - Sex without Consent: Volume 1 (Box 8)
      - Sex without Consent: Volume 2 (Box 8)
      - Reverse Alchemy in Childhood: Turning Gold into Lead (Box 8)
      - The Nature and Dynamics of Domestic Violence (Box 8)
      - Hope and Power for your Personal Finances (Box 8)
      - Acquaintance Rape and Sexual Assault: A Prevention Manual (5th Ed.) (Box 8)
      - The Campus Community Confronts Sexual Assault (Box 8)
      - Reasonable Efforts Checklist for Dependency Cases Involving DV (Box 8)
      - Managing Your Divorce: A Guide for Battered Women (Box 8)
      - Comprehensive Issue Spotting: A Tool for Civil Attorneys Representing Victims of Domestic and Dating Violence, Sexual Assault and Stalking (Box 8)
      - Navigating Custody and Visitation Evaluations in Cases with Domestic Violence: A Judge's Guide (Box 8)
      - A Judicial Guide to Child Safety in Custody Cases (Box 8)
  - Posters and Campaign Materials, Series 18
    - Posters and Signs
      - Center for Relationship Abuse Awareness Table Banner Sign (Box 1)
      - Amnesty International Posters (Box 1)
      - University Poster Campaign (Box 1)
        Intern project. See University Poster Campaign at www.stoprelationshipabuse.org.
    - Other Campaign Materials
      - Center IPV Campaign Materials, Buttons, Pins (Box 9)
  - Documents/Trainings about Backlash against the Movement to End Violence Against Women, Series 19
    - Articles Related to the Anti-Feminist Backlash, Gender Symmetry Proponents
      Backlash stands for anti-feminist backlash. Gender symmetry proponents (or research) and gender neutrality (or research) proponents either actively or unintentionally contribute to backlash theorists. Gender neutrality in this context is different than encouraging gender neutrality in direct service, which is important. Anti-feminist backlash theorists challenge the progress of the movement by promoting the inaccurate concept that women are equally as violent as men and are equally likely to be perpetrators, discounting or ignoring research that finds that up to 95% of relationship abuse and 99% of sexual assault is perpetrated by a man against a woman. The research that fuels the anti-feminist backlash is largely completed with ineffective research models and inaccurate data.
      - Good Articles (Box 25)
        See Box 2 for Backlash/Gender Neutrality folder with more articles.
      - Bad Articles (Box 25)
        Includes some notes on the articles.
      - Teen Research (Box 25)
        A concerning trend is that teen research was often reporting equal rates of perpetration by boys and girls based on inaccurate research methodology and questions that did not control for context, such as self defense. In addition, many reports used gender neutral language such as "one in four youth" instead of "one in four girls."
      - Bad Articles - General (Box 25)
      - Michael Johnson Articles (Box 25)
        On first glance, it may look like Johnson is contributing to a new analysis of gender and violence with his typologies. Once we dig deeper, however, we see that he is contributing to the goals of gender neutralization proponents and antifeminist groups through his conclusions. Includes notes on the articles.
        See electronic records series for Johnson Handout 9.15.08.
      - False Allegations (Box 25)
      - Miscellaneous Articles (Box 25)
    - AAA Committee: Backlash Committee (Advance the Analysis to Action)
      Baran was co-chair of this state committee to respond to the Anti-Feminist Backlash Movement
      - AAA Subcommittee (Box 25)
      - AAA (Box 25)
      - CA Partnership to End DV: AAA Subcommittee Meeting, 2007 Nov 27 (Box 25)
      - CA Partnership to End DV: AAA Subcommittee Meeting, 2008 Mar 10 (Box 25)
      - Father's Rights (Box 25)
      - Backlash Legislation (Box 25)
    - Backlash Presentations
      - Backlash Presentation List (Box 25)
        List of 8 national and local presentations on backlash.
      - Asian Women's Shelter, 2009 Mar 4 (Box 25)
      - AAA, 2008 Sep 8 (Box 25)
        Presentation for CPEDV's annual statewide coalition conference.
      - Greenbook Backlash: The Impact of Men's and Father's Rights Groups on Efforts to Address Domestic Violence and Child Welfare.", 2009 Jun 4 (Box 25)
        Presented at the Greenbook National Summit (10 year reflective) with Jeffrey Edleson and Anne Menard.
    - Miscellaneous
      - Miscellaneous: Gender Symmetry Review (Box 25)
      - Miscellaneous: Primary Aggressor Tool (Box 25)
  - Greenbook Initiative Documents/Trainings, Series 20
    Effective Intervention in Domestic Violence & Child Maltreatment Cases: Guidelines for Policy and Practice, also known as the "Greenbook," is a set of recommendations designed to help dependency courts and child welfare and domestic violence agencies better serve families experiencing violence. The Family Violence Department of the National Council of Juvenile & Family Court Judges (NCJFCJ) brought together a diverse, expert committee to develop the Greenbook over many months. Its recommendations are being used, formally and informally, by hundreds of communities across the nation and around the world. From 2000-2007, the United States Departments of Health and Human Services and Justice funded six demonstration sites across the country. The demonstration sites joined battered women’s organizations, child protection agencies, the courts, and other partners in implementing the Greenbook’s recommendations.
    Baran worked with three of the six counties selected, starting as a cross-trainer: St. Louis County, MO, (2002-2004) Santa Clara County, CA (2004-2005), San Francisco County, CA (2005-2007). She also presented at the National Summit in 2009, which was the 10 year anniversary and a gathering of experts across the country.
    - Greenbook Cross-Reference List (Box 18)
      For Greenbook Guidelines file, see Box 6; for MCADomestic Violence Greenbook Committee file, see Box 26; for Greenbook 6.4.09 Backlash file, see Box 25; for Greenbook Cross-Training file, Greenbook Training 2004, and Santa Clara County Greenbook Project: Implementation Team Meeting (8.18.2006), see Box 18; for Greenbook 6.16.06 files, see Box 23; for Greenbook Conference 2009 (6.2-4.09, Jackson Hole, WY) file, Greenbook Summit 6.4.09 file, The Greenbook Summit Planning Meeting (11.6-7.08) folder, and Greenbook Advocacy 6.4.09 file, see Box 28.
    - Guidelines for Policy Practice The Green Book: Effective Intervention in Domestic Violence Child Maltreatment Cases (Box 18)
    - If I Knew Then What I Know Now: Project Leadership in Multi-System Change Efforts to Address the Co-Occurrence of Domestic Violence and Child Maltreatment (Box 18)
    - St. Louis Greenbook Planning Phase Report, 2001-2002 (Box 18)
    - DSS Manual for Domestic Violence Advocates (Box 18)
    - Published Guidelines and Prep
      Baran published "Helping Battered Women: A Guide for Domestic Violence Advocates on the Co-Occurrence of Domestic Violence & Child Maltreatment." Includes original research, focus groups, articles, prep.
      - Helping Battered Women: A Guide for Domestic Violence Advocates on the Co-Occurrence of Domestic Violence Child Maltreatment (Box 18)
        Hired by Greenbook as a consultant, Baran wrote the original draft for this manual and later Lauren Litton became a co-author. These were guidelines meant for the State of Missouri on how a Domestic Violence advocate should respond to cases where there is a co-occurrence of Domestic Violence and CM.
      - Baran Paper: Needs Assessment Domestic Violence CM (Box 18)
        This was the paper that Baran wrote for the MSW program (see Evaluation of Program and Services in Box 27) as a Needs Assessment for the guidelines; this included a focus group and questionnaire Entitled: "A Needs Assessment: Domestic Violence Service Providers Response to CM."
      - Focus Group Materials Domestic Violence CM (Box 18)
      - DV/CM Focus Group, 2003 Jul 22 (Box 18)
      - Child's Focus Group, 2003 Oct 28 (Box 18)
      - Greenbook Self-Study (Box 18)
      - Guidelines (Box 18)
      - Guidelines Prep (Box 18)
    - Trainings
      - Greenbook Cross-Training (Santa Clara, CA), 2004 (Box 18)
      - Greenbook Training (Santa Clara, CA), 2004 (Box 18)
        Baran presented. This was the training where a CPS worker, after watching a video about a man slitting his wife's throat in front of their six year-old child, stated "How could she let her child see this?" This was one of Baran's influences in starting the Center.
      - Santa Clara County Greenbook Project: Implementation Team Meeting, 2016 Aug 18 (Box 18)